Adam Carpenter

Software Developer

adamcarpenter86@gmail.com

303.918.2290

in adam-joseph-carpenter

Adami1232

www.AdamJCarpenter.com

SKILLS

SOFTWARE DEVELOPMENT

Terminal Atom/VS Code Agile Development HTML5 CSS3/SASS JavaScript – ES6 jQuery

Typescript/RxJS

Angular 2/4/5 Material Design

React/Router/Redux

React Native

Responsive Design

NodeJS/ExpressJS

RethinkDB

TDD

Mocha

Chai

Selenium/Protractor

Enzyme

Jest

ADDITIONAL

Project Management Graphic Design Adobe Photoshop Adobe Illustrator Telecommunications

Telecommunications Cabling Home and Business Security Data Center Rack & Stack Event Planning

Microsoft Office

EDUCATION

Turing School of Software + Design.

01-2017 - 07-201

Front End Web Development

Mentor to current student body

SUMMARY

After 3 years in telecommunications and 10 in the music industry, I enrolled at Turing School of Software. I graduated early to join the Network Automation team within the Advanced Engineering branch of the second-largest cable-operating company in the country, Charter. As an integral member of the UI development team, I created enterprise software to visualize, troubleshoot and increase the efficiency of Charter's network engineering teams.

PROJECTS

Symphony

- Enterprise software built with Angular 2/4/5 leveraging Typescript, RxJS, AgGrid, D3, Material Design, Express Gateway, and more.
- Network visualization and troubleshooting tool allowing network engineers to run troubleshooting and configuration commands and scripts on customized groups of devices across the country.

Website: Enterprise Software – See portfolio for example

GigWrangler

- React/Redux JS app developed to allow musicians to connect with music venues across the country through a smooth interface.
- Utilized Google Maps API, Google Map Clustering, and tested with Mocha and Enzyme,
- Created custom data-set of 3300+ music venues throughout the US using a Python web scraper and Google maps API to visibly pinpoint locations.

Website: https://adamj1232.github.io/Gig-Wrangler/
GitHub Repo: https://github.com/Adamj1232/Gig-Wrangler

MovieTracker

• React/Redux/Router JS app with Node/Express backend, developed to allow movie fans to login, save favorite and learn about newly release films using an intuitive interface.

Website: https://movie--tracker.herokuapp.com/

GitHub Repo: https://github.com/Adamj1232/movie-tracker

CloudKicker/RAIngULAR

- Fully accessible, on-demand and responsive weather app built in both ReactJS and Angular2, tested with Mocha, Protractor and Enzyme.
- CloudKicker is built using React and RAIngULAR with Angular2.

Website: https://adamj1232.github.io/CloudKicker-WeatherForecast-ReactProject/

Website: https://adamj1232.github.io/RAIngular/

GitHub Repo: https://github.com/Adamj1232/CloudKicker-WeatherForecast-ReactProject

GitHub Repo: https://github.com/Adamj1232/RAIngular

EXPERIENCE

Charter Communications – Advanced Engineering

JUL 2017 - PRESENT

Software Engineer / UI Engineer — Englewood, CO

- Responsible for creating enterprise software for internal usage by operations and network engineers
- UI/UX development, automated testing, interface driven network automation, development an API Gateway, data modeling and some digital design of app logos.
- Angular 2/4/5/6, RxJS, SASS, Express Gateway, Material Design, Node, RethinkDB, Redis, Python, Flask

RossComm

JUL 2013 - DEC 2016

Lead Low Voltage Technician — Westminster, CO

- Responsible for installing, troubleshooting and training on large workstation projects.
- Lead a team on large scale telephone, security and server-room installations